Gonçalo Andrade de Oliveira

■ goncalo.27@hotmail.com | (351) 934-669-354 | Santo Tirso, Portugal

Portfolio - https://g0dz4ll0.github.io/ LinkedIn - https://g0dz4ll0.github.io/

SUMMARY

I'm a passionate and motivated game developer with strong skills in problem solving and gameplay programming. I have developed a plethora of different projects during my professional and academic career that provided me with experience in different tools and frameworks, particularly with Unity and C#. I'm also a fast learner, being able to pick up on new tools and methodologies very quickly.

EXPERIENCE

Critical Path | https://goncalo-oliveira.itch.io/critical-path

Programmer Oct. 2021 - Dec. 2021

Source Code: https://github.com/g0dz4ll0/Critical-Path

- Worked on Critical Path with a team of 6 people, a "Tower Defense" game where the player has to defend an organism against invading covid-19 variants.
- Responsible for implementing the whole UI and HUD including its animations and functionality providing responsive and intuitive menus like the tower shop.
- Also, as a solo programmer in the project I helped implement all other mechanics of the game including the AI, camera movement and other game logic.

Call of Pets: Modern Wizard | https://vitormoreira.itch.io/call-of-pets-modern-wizard

Programmer Jan. 2023 - Dec. 2023

Source Code: https://github.com/g0dz4ll0/Brackeys-Game[am]

- Initially developed for a Game Jam but which development extended for a little longer. Responsible for the implementation of most systems and mechanics along with another programmer.
- Worked along with a team of 4 developers in a highly dynamic environment and under pressure due to time constraints, still being able to correspond to our expectations and building an enjoyable game;
- Helped on the development of the power-up system, implemented the enemy AI, the player
 movement and an enemy wave system along with its UI implementations and animations.

Project-Survival | https://g0dz4ll0.github.io/projects/projectsurvival.html Solo Dev

May. 2022 - Present

Source Code: https://github.com/g0dz4ll0/Project-Survival

- Decided to tackle a challenge as a solo dev with a personal hobby project that consists of a survival game with procedural generated levels inspired by Valheim with a cartoony style;
- Created a building system along with its UI functionalities including tooltips, an inventory and a collision detection system;
- Built a procedural generation system using the Unity terrain system based on a seed providing a huge variety in gameplay.
- Implemented a crafting, a hunger and thirst system with its respective UI representations, informations and tooltips.

EDUCATION

Instituto Politécnico de Bragança

BS, Video Game Design Mirandela, Bragança Sep. 2019 - Oct. 2022

Instituto Politécnico do Cávado e do Ave

MS, Video Game Engineering Barcelos, Braga. Oct. 2022 - Present

LANGUAGES

Portuguese Native English C2

SKILLS